She loves everything about her son...except who he is.
Prayers for Bobby is a drama, history, tv movie
film directed by Russell Mulcahy.
Bobby Griffith was his mother's favorite son, the perfect all-American boy growing
up under deeply religious influences in Walnut Creek, California.
Bobby was also gay.
Struggling with a conflict no one knew of, much less
understood, Bobby finally came out to his family.
Mary Griffith, played by Sigourney Weaver.
Robert Griffith, played by Henry Czerny.
Bobby Griffith, played by Ryan Kelley.
Ed Griffith, played by Austin Nichols.
Joy Griffith, played by Carly Schroeder.
David, played by Scott Bailey.
Prayers for Bobby is a televised drama film that premiered
on the Lifetime network on January 24, 2009.
The film is based on the book of the same name by Leroy F.
Aarons, which is itself based on the true story of the life and legacy of Bobby Griffith, a
young gay man who killed himself in 1983 due to his mother's homophobia.
Ryan Kelley stars as Bobby Griffith and Sigourney
Weaver portrays his mother Mary.
The film was watched by more than 6 million
viewers during its two-day initial run.
It received positive reviews from critics and was nominated for two Primetime Emmy Awards: Outstanding Television Movie and Outstanding Lead
Actress in a Limited Series or Movie for Weaver, who was also nominated for a Golden Globe Award, and a Screen Actors Guild Award.
The film explores themes of coming out, suicide, based on novel
or book, parent child relationship, homophobia.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking.